Kim Thompson

bykimthompson@gmail.com

Profile

A software developer with over 3 years of experience creating applications for a wide variety of platforms. A jack-of-all-trades who is passionate about the frontend and comfortable with backend and mobile.

Languages

JavaScript, React, Vue, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Node.js, Swift, Objective-C, C#, ASP.NET, Xamarin, PHP, Python, Java, SQL

Experience

Web Developer, Minnesota Public Radio

August 2018-Present

- Developing websites and other tools for all of American Public Media's offerings, mostly working with React and Rails.
- Helping the web department move away from having custom Rails backends for each web application, instead creating a generalized backend client and using more of React's advanced capabilities on a per-site basis.
- Specializing in visualization and helping the newsroom tell complex stories better.

Associate Software Developer, Design Center Inc.

February 2017-August 2018

- Developed applications for iOS, web and Windows. Some of these were large and were started by others, while others were small and left to me alone.
- Managed client and project manager expectations, often helping them see better solutions that they did not know to ask for.
- Wrote the company's frontend web standards and taught the designers how to write HTML and CSS. Stressed to managers that JavaScript development should be done by software developers.

Technology LDP Trainee, Ameriprise Financial

July 2015-February 2017

- Role 1: Redesigned and wrote the frontend for Ameriprise's advisor compensation application homepage, working within the limits of the old JSP application.
- Role 2: Conducted working sessions to complete disaster recovery plans for all of my department's applications.
- Role 3: Tested and polished a client-facing dashboard built with Backbone.js.

Product Strategy/Design Intern, Pearson VUE

May 2014-August 2014

- Researched ideas for new products and pitched those ideas, creating mockups ranging from simple wireframes to working HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Validated my choices with user feedback, learning the principles of user experience design.

Interactives Intern, Slate

May 2013-August 2013

- Created visualizations for the web as directed by the interactives editor, picking up my initial web development skills on the way.
- Dabbled in JavaScript visualization libraries and figured out ways to use programming to collect unique datasets.
- Wrote short blog posts and took care of early research and interviews for larger stories.

Education

University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota

GPA 3.3

Bachelor of Arts, Computer Science Bachelor of Arts, Journalism